少
年
谢尔顿
我从小喜欢火车
I've always loved trains.
事实上
In fact,
如果我理论物理学的工作当初没成
if my career in theoretical physics hadn't worked out,
我的后备计划
my backup plan
是打算当一个职业检票员
was to become a professional ticket taker.
或者是流浪汉
Or hobo.
当我发现火车能让我
And when I figured out that trains allowed me
证明牛顿第一定律...
to prove Newton's first law--
任何运动中的物体
an object in motion stays in motion
其速度的大小与方向都不会改变
with the same speed and in the same direction
除非有合外力施加于这物体
unless acted upon by an unbalanced force--
我感到了尼尔·阿姆斯特朗登月时
I felt like Neil Armstrong on the moon,
那种孤独又快乐的感觉
alone and happy.
谢利  晚饭做好了
Shelly, dinner's ready!
我不管你有多笨
I don't care how dimwitted you are.
但科学原理肯定能让你笑开怀
Scientific principles have to make you smile.
当然  我1989年在德州东部
Of course, nobody I knew in East Texas
所认识的人中  没人在乎牛顿物理学
in 1989 cared about Newtonian physics.
他们唯一在意的"牛顿"
The only Newtons they cared about
是艺人维恩·牛顿与牛顿饼干
were Wayne and Fig.
谢尔顿  你再不来
Sheldon, if you don't get in here,
-我就去舔你的牙刷  -马上来
- I'm gonna lick your toothbrush! - Coming!
那是我姐姐
That's my sister.
她已经不是第一回干这事了
And she's done it before.
你窝在房里搞啥狗屁玩意呢
What the hell were you doing out there?
乔治  说话文明点
George, language.
我哪里不文明了  所以呢
What language? So?
我在研究维运动学
I was exploring dimensional kinematics.
承认吧  他是领养的
Admit it-- he's adopted.
我有个双胞胎姐姐  怎么可能是被领养的
How can I be adopted when I have a twin sister?
用脑啊  猴哥  用脑
Think, monkey, think.
够了
That's enough.
没人是被领养的
No one's adopted.
真希望我是
I wish I was.
现在让别人领养你也还来得及
That can still be arranged.
来祷告吧
Now, let's pray.
稍等一下
A moment, please.
-随他去  -他为什么不能跟家人握手
- Leave him be. - He can hold hands with his family.
握一下又不会死
It won't kill him.
这可难说
We don't know that.
乔治  你吃晚饭前洗手了吗
Georgie, did you wash your hands before dinner?
或者说  你这周有洗手过吗
Or even this week?
关你屁事啊
None of your business.
所以我戴手套
Hence the mittens.
感谢主  赐予我们桌上的食物
Thank you, God, for this food we're about to receive
为我们的身体提供营养
and for the nourishment of our bodies,
也保佑准备这餐点的人
and bless the hands that prepared it.
阿门
Amen.
为啥没有炸薯球
How come we ain't got no tater tots?
我昨晚做过炸薯球了
I made tater tots last night.
我永远都会选炸薯球而不选薯泥
I'd take tater tots over mashed potaters any day.
我做啥你就吃啥
Just eat what I made you.
我们明天能吃炸薯球吗
Can we at least have tater tots tomorrow?
因为这样的家庭晚餐
It was family dinners like this
让我学会了大西洋中部口音
that led me to adopt a mid-Atlantic accent.
诺贝尔奖得主
Nobel Prize winners...
吃啥炸薯球啊
ought not be orderin' tater tots.
有人期待周一开学吗
Everybody excited to start school Monday?
我
I am.
大概吧
I guess so.
乔治呢
Georgie?
上高一  这可是件大事
Freshman year, that's a big deal.
当我想到他要跟我读同一年级
How can I be excited when he's gonna be
我就兴奋不起来
in the same grade as me?
别担心  乔治  我没打算
Don't worry, Georgie, I'm not planning
要在高一读太久
on being in the ninth grade for very long.
反正他不再跟我读同一年级
All I know is he's not in the same grade as me anymore,
我真是高兴坏了
and I'm thrilled.
祝你上课画手指画玩得开心
Good luck with your finger painting.
你在高中绝对会被人扁得屁滚尿流
You're gonna get your ass kicked in high school.
注意用词
Hey, language.
我才不会被揍
I'm not going to be assaulted.
高中可是高等教育的殿堂
High school is a haven for higher learning.
我的神啊
Oh, dear God.
说到神  谁明天要跟我去教堂
Speaking of God, who's going to church with me tomorrow?
我去不了
I can't.
我要跟其他教练见面
I'm meeting with the other coaches.
不能去完教堂后再见面吗
You can't meet after church?
不行  玛丽  不能等去完教堂再见
No, Mary, I can't meet after church.
乔治呢
Georgie?
我得去学习战术手册
I got to study my playbook.
我陪你去吧  妈妈
I'll go with you, Mom.
你为什么去
Why are you going?
你都不信上帝
You don't believe in God.
不啊  但是我信妈妈
No, but I believe in Mom.
总比不去好  米希
I'll take it. Missy?
去不了  希瑟找我去...
Can't, Heather asked me to...
-你得去  -操他妈的
- You're goin'. - Son of a bitch.
米希
Missy...
不许在餐桌上扔东西
Don't you throw something at the dinner table.
小乔治
George Jr.
生物学家珍·古德研究人猿得去非洲
Jane Goodall had to go to Africa to study apes.
我在家吃晚饭就行
I just had to go to dinner.
不许在餐桌上丢东西
Never at the dinner table!
快停手  乔治
You knock that off, George!
不许还手
D-Do not retaliate!
♪ 前进吧  基督教的士兵 ♪
♪ Onward, Christian soldiers ♪
Onward, Christian Soldiers
♪ 向战场前进 ♪
♪ Marching as to war ♪
♪ 带着耶稣的十字 ♪
♪ With the cross of Jesus ♪
♪ 向前进 ♪
♪ Going on before. ♪
在《马太福音》第九章第四节  耶稣说
In Matthew nine, verse four, Jesus said,
" 你们为什么心里怀着恶念呢 "
" Why would you entertain evil thoughts in your hearts? "
你的心里有恶念吗
Do you have evil thoughts?
我只是觉得这一段我用不上
I just don't think this part applies to me.
没关系  安静听讲就行了
That's fine. Be quiet and listen.
我才九岁
I'm only nine years old.
大多数恶念要等青春期才产生
Most evil doesn't start till puberty.
您好
Hello.
你有恶念吗
Do you have evil thoughts?
现在就有一个
I'm having one right now.
真的吗  是什么
Really? What is it?
等我们回到家  我要踢你的蛋蛋
When we get home, I'm gonna kick your little balls.
你踢不了  它们还没垂入阴囊
You can't. They haven't descended yet.
-妈  -怎么
- Mom? - What?
我什么时候可以人熟蛋落呢
When should I be expecting my testicles?
这孩子有什么毛病
What is wrong with him?
他才没有毛病
Nothin' is wrong with him.
转回去  不然小心我揍飞你的狗眼
Now, turn around before I knock your lights out.
不停地想这些东西
...think continually on these things.
善念能导致好事发生
A good thought leads to a good thing.
你能在体内感到  你能在...
You feel it in your body. You feel it in your...
我的妈妈就是我的基督教士兵
My mom was my Christian soldier.
声明一下  我的蛋蛋在我15岁时落下了
And for the record, they descended when I was 15.
正常应该在出生至一岁前从腹腔落入阴囊
谢利  这是你暑假最后一天了
Shelly, it's your last day of summer.
快出去玩儿吧
Go out and enjoy it.
但我得先学习学生手册啊
But I have to learn the student handbook.
你知道特殊发型
Ooh, did you know extreme hairstyles,
山羊胡与小胡子都是不允许的吗
goatees and mustaches are not allowed?
我不知道
I didn't.
这规定让我个人感到安心许多
I personally find that very reassuring.
看看这多么风光明媚的一天
Look what a beautiful day it is.
去玩吧
Go play.
去玩  人生有这么简单就好了
GO play? if only life were that simple.
好  我玩了
There, I played.
谢尔顿
Hey, Sheldon!
你好啊  比利·斯巴克斯
Hello, Billy Sparks.
你好  玛蒂尔达·斯巴克斯
Hello, Matilda Sparks.
我听说你明天要去上高中啦
I heard you're going to high school tomorrow.
是啊
I am.
你得找一个新的
You're going to have to find someone else
在游乐场折磨的对象了
to torment on the playground.
折磨是什么意思
Torment?
就是恶意骚扰
It means to maliciously harass.
骚鸟
Herass
真好笑
That's funny.
跟你聊天挺愉快
Well, this was nice.
二傻子
Hey, doofus!
妈
Mom!
-乖女孩  妈
- Good girl. - Mom!
我能怎么办  他脚也在长大
What am I supposed to do? His feet are growing.
为什么不能让他穿乔治的旧鞋
Why can't he wear Georgie's old shoes?
他连手都不愿意跟他牵
He won't hold your hand.
你觉得他会愿意把脚
You think he's gonna put his feet
塞进他哥哥的臭鞋里吗
in his brother's smelly shoes?
我们他妈总得找地方省出钱
Well, we damn well better cut back somewhere.
你能不能小声点
Will you please keep your voice down?
他们又在为你吵架
They're fighting about you again.
他们是为钱吵架
They're fighting about money.
这是婚姻中常见的争吵话题
It's a common argument in marriages.
熄灯睡觉啦
Lights out.
明天是大日子
Big day tomorrow.
妈妈
Mom?
我们家有经济问题吗
Do we have financial problems?
这事不用你担心
Don't you worry about that.
我们没事
We are fine.
快睡觉
Now, go to sleep.
她在说谎
She's lying.
她是为了安慰你才这么说
She just said that to make you feel better.
妈妈才不说谎
Mom doesn't lie.
的确  她相信地球是上帝花六天做成
Sure, she thinks the Earth was made in six days,
但她只是好骗  而不是个骗子
but that's 'cause she's gullible, not a liar.
妈妈
Mom,
谢尔顿找不到他的领结
Sheldon can't find his bowtie.
真的吗  我帮他把衣服都摆好了啊
Really? I laid it out for him.
别管他  玛丽  他不需要领结
Leave it alone, Mary. He doesn't need a bowtie.
这是他第一天上高中  他想穿什么就让他穿
It's his first day of school. Let him wear what he wants.
妈  我找不到我的领结
Mom, I can't find my bowtie!
老天爷啊  他为什么要戴领结
Dear Lord, why's he got to wear a bowtie?
我能坐你的车去上学吗
Can I drive in with you?
可以
Sure.
大家都会知道他是你弟弟
Everybody's gonna know he's your brother.
你要难受了
It's gonna be awful for you.
让她闭嘴
Tell her to shut up.
她说的也没错
She's not wrong.
绝对在这里
It's got to be here.
不在  真的不在
It's not. It's not!
谢利  冷静  我们会找到的
Shelly, stay calm. We'll find it.
我的领结不见啦  我的领结
My tie is gone! My tie is gone!
谢利  你其实不需要戴领结
Shelly, you don't really need a tie.
我必须得找到它  我一定要找到领结
I have to find my tie. I have to find my tie.
马上回来
Be right back.
质子教授就有戴领结
Professor Proton wears a bowtie!
小乔治
George Junior,
把他的领结给我
give me back that bowtie right now!
-我没拿  -不许骗我
- I didn't take it! - Don't you lie to me!
我没说谎
I'm not lying!
-走着瞧  -别进我房间
- We'll see about that. - Stay out of my room!
她会搜到你的黄色书刊
She's gonna find your dirty magazines.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你今天惨啦
You are not having a good day.
他没偷拿
Hey, he didn't take it.
-那领结上哪去了  -帮我找我的领结
- Then what happened to it?! - Help me find my bowtie!
我去浴室看看
I'll check in the bathroom!
是我拿的
I took it.
你为什么拿他领结
Why would you do that?
玛丽  那孩子才九岁
Mary, the boy is nine years old
现在要去上高中
and going into high school.
这还不够奇怪吗
Isn't that weird enough?
-给我  -别这样
- Give it to me. - Come on.
别光想着谢尔顿
It's not just Sheldon.
小乔治会跟他是同班同学呢
Georgie's gonna be in class with him.
不在浴室
Not in the bathroom!
拿来
Give it.
你想玩一个车上游戏吗
Would you like to play a driving game?
不太想  我总是输
Not really. I always lose.
我知道  所以才好玩啊
I know. That's why it's fun.
比如找车牌号是质数
How about license plates with prime numbers
-后面是常...  -我们就聊天行吗
- followed by a cons...? - Why don't we just talk?
好的
Very well.
你明白学校里会有人因为你太聪明
You understand that some people are gonna be intimidated by you
而感到威胁吧
'cause of how smart you are?
他们也有可能会认可我的聪明才智
Or maybe they'll recognize my intellect
进而推选我当他们的领导
and make me their leader.
主啊  请保佑我的孩子
Lord, look after my son.
保佑他不被人塞进运动包里
Don't let him get stuffed in a gym bag.
天啊
Oh, dear.
那男生有个露出的刺青
That boy has an exposed tattoo.
是啊
He does.
不知道他知不知道
I wonder if he knows
那样违反着装规范
that's in violation of the dress code.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
咱们别戴领结了好吗
how about we lose the bowtie?
为什么
Why?
亲爱的  你看大家  没人戴领结啊
Look around, honey. None of the other kids are wearing one.
或许我可以引领潮流啊
Well, perhaps I'll start a fad.
你不会的  相信妈妈
No, you won't. Please trust Mommy.
好吧  这样吧
All right, tell you what.
你如果摘下来  这周末
You take it off, and this weekend,
我就带你去逛睿侠电器行
I'll take you to RadioShack.
美国老牌电器行  主要卖电器与各种线
你还好吗
You doing okay?
大概吧
I guess.
我闻到了氨水味
I smell ammonia.
他们肯定刚刚仔细清理过校园
They must've done a thorough cleaning recently.
我喜欢
I like that.
还记得如果有人骚扰你  你该怎么说吗
And remember, if anybody bothers you, what do you say?
我爸是橄榄球教练
My dad's a football coach.
-还有呢  -我哥是橄榄球员
- And? - My brother's a football player.
很好
Good.
妈  你看
Hey, Mom, look.
那女生怀孕了
That girl's pregnant.
恭喜
Congratulations.
里面真是让人想吐
Well, that was revolting.
好的  这是你的班级教室
All right. This is your homeroom.
需要我陪你进去吗
Do you want me to go in with you?
虽然刚才在厕所时挺希望你在  但不用
No. Although I could've used you in the restroom.
好的   那...
Okay, well...
祝你今天一切顺利
You have a good day.
我放学后会来接你
And I'll pick you up after school,
就在我们进来的那个出口等你
same door we came in.
你是哭了还是过敏犯了
Are you crying or having an allergy attack?
过敏
Allergies.
估计是那些氨水
It's probably the ammonia.
应该是
Probably.
好  开始学习吧
Okay. Let the learning begin.
大家好
All right, everybody,
请叫我马克艾罗伊女士
my name is Ms. MacElroy.
我将会是你们的班导
In addition to being your homeroom teacher,
我也会是部分同学的英语课老师
I'll be seeing some of you in my English class,
也会跟部分的同学在排球场上见
and some of you on the volleyball court.
跟大家简单介绍一下
Just to give you a little history,
我在梅德福教了29年
I've been here at Medford for 29 years...
我教过你们一些人的哥哥姐姐
...I taught some of your older brothers and sisters,
很不幸地  还有一些同学的爸爸妈妈
and sadly, some of your parents.
也算见过各种大小场面了
Not much I haven't seen.
但今天又长了见识
Until today.
我相信大家都清楚我们有个同学
I'm sure you're well aware we have a student with us,
虽然年纪还小
who, despite his young age,
但天赋异禀
is remarkably gifted.
我希望大家能相处融洽
And I expect y'all to make him feel welcome.
谢尔顿  请说
Yes, Sheldon?
根据学生着装与仪容规范
Per the student dress and grooming code,
那个男生的头发过长
this boy's hair is too long,
这个男生在规定范围外
this boy is wearing sports attire
穿着运动服饰
outside of a designated area
这个女生的上衣太透
and this girl's blouse is diaphanous,
这表示我能看到底下的胸罩
which means I can see her brassiere.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会再参考你的意见
I will take that into account.
好
All right.
在第一堂课开始前还有几分钟
We have a few minutes before first period.
我需要大家都填好这些表格
I need y'all to fill out these forms.
怎么了
What?
您违反了仪容规章第48页
Also in violation of the grooming code on page 48,
第5章B小段
article five, subsection B,
您有一点小胡须
you have a bit of a mustache.
这就是个烂主意
This is a stupid idea.
这孩子就不该来上我们学校
This boy does not belong in our school.
别这样维琪  第一天上课而已
Come on Vicky, it's just the first day.
我们大家先全都深呼吸一下
Why don't we all just take a deep breath here?
深个毛呼吸  我的数学课才上5分钟
The hell with that. Five minutes into my math class,
他就开始质疑我的文凭
he questioned my credentials.
一个孩子质疑我违反了卫生条例的情况下
How am I supposed to control a classroom when a kid accuses me
我还怎么管住一个班
of being in breach of the hygiene code?
休伯特  你多洗洗澡也不会死啊
Well, Hubert, it wouldn't kill you to shower a little more often.
乔治  你想说两句吗
George, you want to weigh in here?
奥洛尔罗伯茨大学是一所好大学
Oral Roberts University is a wonderful school.
他说我对他的聪明才智感到威胁
He said I was intimidated by his intelligence,
然后呢
and then,
他提议来当我的领导
he offered to be my leader.
你认识这个奏鸣曲吗
Do you know this sonata?
不认识
No.
你学琴多久了
How long have you played the piano?
我不会弹钢琴
I don't play piano.
乔治  你有什么看法
George, you got any thoughts here?
当然
I certainly do.
玛丽  跟他说
Mary, tell him.
很简单  我们别无选择了
It's simple. We don't have a choice.
你们也努力过了
Well, you gave it a shot.
祝你们的谢尔顿在别的学校...
We wish you luck with Sheldon elsewhere...
不不不
No, no, no.
我们的别无选择
We don't have a choice.
是他只能在这里读书
He's got to stay here.
我们负担不起私立学校
We can't afford private school.
我也没办法在家教他
I sure can't homeschool him.
他已经在做微积分跟欧几里得什么的了
He's doing calculus and Euclidean something or other.
欧几里得几何学
Euclidean geometry.
猜猜我在哪学到的这个
Guess where I learned that.
是是是  我们知道
Yeah, yeah, we know.
我唯一在乎的就是
All I care about is that
我儿子得到了他应得的教育
my son gets the education he deserves,
所以你们这些老师得想办法
so you all are gonna have to figure this out.
教练  你能帮我说两句吗
Coach, can you help me out here, please?
我要被逼死了
'Cause I'm dyin'.
我选择拒绝
I'd rather not.
G小调
G minor.
F调
F.
降E调
E flat.
C小调
C minor.
你有绝对音感
You have perfect pitch.
好吧
Okay.
亲爱的  你真的应该学习音乐
Sweetheart, you should really pursue music.
不了  谢谢  音乐家都吸毒
No, thank you. Musicians take drugs.
有教师洗手间能让我借用一下吗
Is there a faculty restroom I could use?
库珀  斯丁森  你们上
Cooper, Stinson, you're up.
快看  是笨的那个哥哥
Hey, look, it's the dumb brother.
上
Okay.
够了
That's enough.
快停手
Hey, that's enough!
够了  快停手
Hey, hey! That's enough!
小乔治
Georgie.
小乔治  小乔治
Georgie! Georgie!
停下来  给我住手
Stop! Stop!
你发什么神经啊
What the hell is wrong with you?
你还好吗
You okay?
不  一点都不好
No, I'm not okay.
你想去哪
Where you think you're going?
不打了  我再也不打橄榄球了
I quit. I don't want to play anymore!
-什么时候不打了  -现在开始
- Since when? - Since right now!
好了  到底怎么了
All right, what is going on?
你觉得呢
What do you think's going on?!
谢尔顿吗
You mean Sheldon?
你不能让那些事影响到你啊
You can't let that bother you.
难道就没影响到你吗
It doesn't bother you?
你被叫进去校长办公室
You got called to the principal's office.
是啊  的确是不太爽
Yeah, that wasn't so great.
我不能跟他读一个学校
I can't be in the same school as him!
你也没什么别的选择了
Well, I don't see what choice you have.
是啊  从他会说话开始  我再也没选择了
Right. Ever since he could talk, I quit having any choices.
我知道这很难
I know it's hard.
但以你的教练身份告诉你  少唧唧歪歪了
I'm telling you, as your coach, quit your whining,
穿上你的制服  快滚回去继续练习
get your uniform on and you get your ass back out there.
那以我父亲的身份呢
But what about as my dad?
你的父亲今天也很惨
Your dad is having a bad day.
听你教练的话吧
Listen to your coach.
普通的土豆能为时钟提供运转的电力吗
Can a clock be powered by an ordinary potato?
希望可以啊  各位男孩女孩
I hope so, boys and girls,
不然这集将会超无聊啊
or this is going to be a really boring episode.
你需要的物品是...
The supplies you'll need...
为什么不能看卡通《唐老鸭俱乐部》
Why can't we watch DuckTales?
因为看那卡通学不到东西
'Cause we don't learn anything watching DuckTales.
看电视本来就不应该学东西
It's TV; we aren't supposed to learn.
两个鳄鱼夹  还有  我看看...
...two alligator grips and, let's see...
当然啦  还需要个时钟
Of course, a clock.
米希  去旁边  我要跟你弟弟聊两句
Missy, go somewhere else. I need to talk to your brother.
你们为什么不去一边谈  这样我能看...
Why don't you go somewhere else and I can watch Duck...
去
Go!
我恨你们
I hate everybody.
科学时间到啦
It's time for science.
他正要用土豆给时钟提供电力呢
Hey, he was about to power a clock with a potato.
不可能行
Not possible.
-听我说  -我要挨骂了吗
- Now, listen... - Am I in trouble?
没有
No.
或许  乖乖听吧
Maybe. Just listen.
你要是想在学校混下去
You're not gonna make it in this school
你就不能一直举报别人
if you keep ratting people out.
可是他们违反了仪容准则
But they were breaking the grooming codes
还有着装准则啊
and the dress codes.
我看到一个男生他的T恤上写着...
I saw one boy with a T-shirt that said...
-"咬我啊"  -是啊  这...  这样很不好
- Bite me. - Yeah. That-that's terrible.
谢尔顿  我跟你说个小故事
Sheldon, let me tell you a little story.
你想过我们为什么从加尔维斯顿搬到这里吗
Did you ever wonder why we moved from Galveston to Medford?
没有  我通常都是想一些更重要的问题
No. I tend to wonder about the bigger questions.
好吧  我告诉你原因
Okay, well, here's why.
你爸爸本来有个很棒的教练工作
Your dad had a real good coaching job
而我看到了其他大人违反了规则
and I saw some grown-ups breaking rules.
他们做了什么
What'd they do?
挺复杂的  不过呢...
I-It's kind of complicated, but...
橄榄球教练是不允许
football coaches aren't allowed to recruit kids
从别的高中挖角学生到自己队伍的
from other high schools to play on their teams.
你去举发了他们吗
And you told on them?
是啊  你知道发生了什么事吗
Yeah. You know what happened?
正义制裁了那些破坏规矩的人吗
Justice descended upon the rule breakers?
我被炒鱿鱼了  谢尔顿
I got fired, Sheldon.
而且留下了坏名声
And I got a bad reputation.
所以你才喝那么多啤酒
Oh. That's why you drink so much beer.
就当是为自己好  好吗
Just do yourself a favor. Okay?
明天你去上学
Go to school tomorrow,
少管别人闲事
and mind your own business.
好吗
All right?
爸爸
Dad.
你被炒了你难过吗
Are you sad that you got fired?
主要是生气吧
Mostly angry.
但也有吧
But yeah.
也许有点伤心
Maybe a little sad.
好  我们来祷告
All right, let's say grace.
感谢主
Thank you, God,
赐予我们桌上的食物
for this food we are about to receive.
那是我第一次牵我父亲的手
That was the first time I held my father's hand.
阿门
Amen.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
小乔治  等轮到你再拿
Hey, George Jr., wait your turn.
我一直不愿意碰我哥哥的手
I wouldn't touch my brother's hand
直到了17年后才敢
until 17 years later,
这得感谢洗手液的发明
thanks to the invention of Purell.
你知道什么让我觉得安心吗
You know what I find comforting?
什么呢  宝贝
What's that, baby?
在这个充满不确定性的世界
In a world filled with uncertainty,
这地方将会屹立不摇
this place will be here forever.
这家在美国经历了94年的连锁零售电商
在2015年申请了破产保护
谢尔顿  你好吗
Hey, Sheldon, how you doing?